[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 3]
[Danyue Pavilion]
[Nineteen years ago]
Jin Chunqing!
How dare you put poison?
Poison?
I don't know.
You're already on your deathbed,
yet you still refuse to admit it.
My Lady.
Several servants just came in.
Without saying a word,
they took our luggage away.
They said Second Madam ordered them
to move us to another courtyard.
Those who know understand we're moving,
but those who don't might think
we're being kicked out.
Moving to another courtyard?
We were doing fine in this courtyard.
Why do we have to move?
Step aside.
No matter how good this place is,
it's for guests.
Since you've been recorded
in the genealogy,
we have to arrange a new place for you.
Otherwise, if word gets out,
people will think Second Madam
mistreats you as head of the household.
The Yunshui satin fabric
is so black that it's creepy.
Those who don't know
might think you're in mourning.
Fourth Lady, you're precious now.
How can you be tainted with bad luck?
It's better
to throw it away.
No wonder you were chosen by Old Madam.
You're obedient
and well-behaved.
Fourth Lady,
the stage has been set up.
You'd better act with caution.
In the ancestral hall,
I add oil to the eternal lamps every day.
I know it best
that a wick burning too strongly
often won't last until dawn.
Don't end up like your dead mother.
You...
This cloak is Lord Yan's favorite.
He lent it to me by chance.
If he know
it was ruined by you like this,
I wonder if your lifespan is long enough
for you to survive
Lord Yan's fury.
Lord Yan?
Then you must keep it safe.
But don't worry, Nanny.
My mother once taught me
to live and let live.
I'll clean this cloak.
Please lead the way, Nanny.
Okay, Fourth Lady.
This way, please.
Step aside.
This way.
[Hanxiang Parlor]
Mother.
Mother,
why are you so distracted today?
Is it because of newly arrived Qingyuan?
About her,
you should listen little
and ask little.
Especially in front of the two Madams,
you must be very discreet
and avoid making trouble.
I've been warning you for years.
You must keep it in mind.
But Qingyuan
seems gentle and quiet.
She should be as easy to get along with
as Fourth Madam was.
Even when Second Madam moved her
to that dilapidated Danyue Pavilion,
she didn't get angry.
Danyue Pavilion.
Mother?
Are you all right?
Are you worried that something
might go wrong in Danyue Pavilion?
My Lady!
My Lady! Something is wrong!
Somebody, help!
Wake up, My Lady!
What happened?
What's wrong with you, My Lady?
Come back to us, My Lady!
-My Lady!
-Stay away from me!
My Lady.
Why is your face
so pale and bloodless?
Bloodless?
You're talking nonsense.
She doesn't seem to be Fourth Lady now.
Jin Chunqing.
You contemptible creature.
Murderers should pay with their lives.
Why are you here putting on a show
of madness and specters?
You fool.
Who killed your mother?
Who is your enemy?
Haven't you figured it out yet?
Then tell me,
who exactly is it?
Tell me, who exactly is it?
Right.
Tell us,
who is the murderer?
Isn't this murderer
right here in the Xie Residence?
What exactly do you want?
What do I want?
Don't kill me.
Of course I'm here
to seek revenge.
[The Wondrous Being of the Great Void]
Slay all evil.
Subdue all beasts.
By the order of Celestial Master,
divine soldiers, be quick
to obey the command.
Fourth Lady broke the evil miasma
with a blood blade.
Please take a look, everyone.
This crack runs
right through the Jiuquan acupoint.
The evil aura has dispersed.
Although the evil aura
in Danyue Pavilion has dispersed,
Jin Chunqing
seemed to have suffered a great grievance,
resulting in immense resentment.
Even though she vanished,
the remaining evil aura
will still affect the Xie family's fortune
to some extent.
Then...
Then what should we do?
Don't worry, Old Madam.
You just need to restore Danyue Pavilion
to its original state
when Jin Chunqing was here
and purify it with talismans.
And with the power of this mascot
to block the evil,
it'll surely keep the Xie family
safe and sound.
Good.
What about my granddaughter?
Fourth Lady was possessed
by the vengeful spirit
and lost some vital energy.
I'll melt a talisman in water later.
She'll be fine after drinking it.
Thank you, Celestial Master.
Stop asking for trouble here.
Don't think I don't know
what your intentions were last night.
Who are you talking about?
Are you talking about me?
Old Madam,
you have really misunderstood me.
We brought this girl back
specifically to exorcise evil spirits.
If I hadn't arrange for her
to stay in Danyue Pavilion,
where else could she stay?
Besides,
to suppress a ghost,
one has to stand right in front of it.
Enough.
I don't want to argue with you about this.
Right now,
the evil spirit has been eradicated.
You all have heard
what Celestial Master just said.
Qingyuan
must stay in the Xie Residence
to ward off evil spirits.
From now on,
whoever harbors evil intentions
and damages
the Xie family's fortune even a bit,
I won't spare them.
Yes.
My Lady.
Grandmother.
I was in a daze last night.
Did I do something wrong again
and harm the Xie family?
It's nothing.
It's all in the past.
As for the restoration of Danyue Pavilion,
go and handle it immediately.
Yes.
You may all leave.
[The Wondrous Being of the Great Void]
Do you want
a vegetarian cake to fill you up a little?
Here.
Thank you, Grandmother.
Old Madam, you're well-versed in Buddhism,
but Taoism
is somewhat different.
Dao,
formless and shapeless,
is born of all things,
yet not born of itself.
The scriptures,
carrying the words of Dao,
clearly show the path of cultivation,
yet do not reveal themselves.
Old Madam,
there is a side hall in the back
where longevity tablets are served.
Would you like to go with me
and light a lamp?
Thank you, Celestial Master.
So Jin Chunqing totally deserved it.
She even tried to harm her own daughter.
She shot herself in the foot.
In the end, she was slashed
into oblivion by Xie Qingyuan.
What poetic justice.
You're right, My Lady.
I think so, too.
Qingyuan made such a scene last night.
It was a pretty convincing act.
What act?
Nothing.
Be careful.
Don't let the fire burn your clothes.
What are you doing?
Why did you throw away
someone else's wishing ribbon?
[Li Congxin] [Xie Qingru]
Mine naturally belongs in the very center.
No one can outshine me.
Does it look good?
You're
spoiled rotten by your father.
You always want to be the best.
In the future,
if you marry into a family,
you'll definitely be an intolerant madam.
My husband
will naturally only have me by his side.
Then, Second Lady,
have you asked the young master
of the Marquis of Danyang
if he is willing
to only have a wife
and no concubines?
Mother.
Nanny Liu is making fun of me.
I didn't say I'm going to marry Congxin.
Right.
You don't want to marry him.
Then why did you write his name
on your red ribbon?
[Li Congxin] [Xie Qingru]
That's because
he's the person I miss the most.
The person I miss the most?
♪ Spring comes to the long gate,
green grass sprouts ♪
You can't hit me.
Chunqing,
there is a new development
in the corruption case I'm handling.
I need to go check it out immediately.
♪ Red plums bear dewdrops,
bright and serene ♪
Could you look after Run for half a day?
When I come back,
I'll pick him up.
♪ Year by year, time drifts along ♪
Rest assured.
♪ Warmth and chill
of mortal meet and part ♪
♪ No need to heed the wind's soft whisper
and ask about your return ♪
♪ Wild geese soar through deep clouds,
waiting for the moon to rest ♪
Do you want to play?
Let's play together.
♪ Old memories lie heavy,
haunting every dream ♪
♪ Rise and fall take turns ♪
Little Loser.
You daren't play?
♪ Phases of the moon,
unplanned to wax and wane ♪
Come on.
Catch me.
♪ Count fallen blooms,
yet never count all pains of parting ♪
Don't run.
I'll take you downstairs to play tomorrow.
♪ You, tender yet sharp,
with thorns by your side ♪
Sure.
I saw there are
a lot of wild pheasants downstairs.
Those are wild ducks.
No matter if they're pheasants or ducks,
♪ Like a dim yet blazing candle ♪
let's go downstairs
and catch them tomorrow.
Sure.
Let's get a net and catch a bunch.
Who's still up so late?
You little rascal.
♪ The wind and rain sigh,
the road stretches far ♪
You're so naughty.
You're a bad influence on Run.
♪ Blossoms drift with streams,
affections softly stir ♪
♪ Half real, half illusion;
one cup of spring awakes me ♪
Run,
go to sleep early.
Be a good boy.
I'll make you lots of yummy food tomorrow.
♪ Burned and released,
held by fate's hand ♪
Okay.
Good boy.
♪ Greet the soft, mild evening breeze
and homebound sail to land ♪
♪ Slim moonbeams
weave tangled dreams all night ♪
♪ Lonely home boat glides slow
through dark twilight ♪
♪ I walk and gaze; one cup of spring
fades to lingering cheer ♪
Let's go catch fish tomorrow.
I can't swim.
You can't do anything.
Little Loser.
Fine.
You can do many things.
I think
you're more like a naughty monkey.
Little Loser.
Little Monkey.
See? You can't catch me.
Give it to me.
No.
Mom,
you look so beautiful today.
Come here,
I'll do your hair too.
I'm
going to see an old friend later.
After I see her,
we'll move, okay?
Move?
Where are we moving to?
♪ Burned and released,
held by fate's hand ♪
To a place
where it's always spring
and flowers are blooming all year.
♪ Greet the soft, mild evening breeze
and homebound sail to land ♪
As long as you're with me,
I'll go anywhere.
♪ Slim moonbeams
weave tangled dreams all night ♪
♪ Lonely home boat glides slow
through dark twilight ♪
Mom, can we take Little Loser with us?
♪ I walk and gaze; one cup of spring
fades to lingering cheer ♪
Little Loser.
Come down.
♪ I chant and sigh; one cup of spring,
drunk through turns of year ♪
You.
Don't give people nicknames causally.
Later,
you and Run go out
and buy some of your favorite sweets.
Thank you, Mom.
Come.
-Come catch me.
-Give it back.
Slow down.
Give it back.
Something's wrong.
What are those people doing in your house?
Come with me, quick!
Mother!
What was that sound?
Chase them.
Up there.
Search.
Mom.
Run!
Mom!
Hurry up.
This way.
Let me go!
Get in!
Over there!
Hurry up!
Mom!
Mom.
Let me go!
I'm going to find my mom.
Your mom is already dead.
She is still alive.
Before dawn,
-I went home.
-Let go!
My mom and my younger brother.
All 73 people of our Shen family
were killed by them.
After you passed out last night,
I saw it was safe,
so I went back and took a look.
I didn't expect...
Why don't you cry?
My tears
have dried up since last night.
Without Mom,
I have no home.
What should we do?
How will we survive?
We must remember all of this.
When we grow up,
we must bring the truth to light
and bring the sinners to justice.
Every blood debt
has a name
and must be paid off.
My mom
was the best mom in the world.
I'll make those
who killed her
suffer dearly for this.
My father left this for me.
Take it.
When we meet again,
we'll recognize each other by this.
Are you leaving?
They're looking for me all over the city.
I can't stay in Hengtang anymore.
I don't even know if I can survive.
Trust me.
One day,
I'll definitely return to Hengtang.
We'll surely meet each other again.
Okay.
We have a deal.
When you return to Hengtang,
we'll meet here again.
Later, I learned
his name is Shen Run.
He is the one I've been missing.
Last night,
I was haunted by an evil spirit.
Its face was deathly pale and terrifying.
I took a closer look
and found it was the dead estate manager.
He lay on my bed and refused to leave.
He, weeping blood, asked me
to get justice for him, otherwise...
Otherwise, he would take me with him.
I'll definitely find out the truth
and get justice for that estate manager.
A case
cannot be solved overnight.
Your Lordship,
have you thought of
a countermeasure?
I've already asked a master for a ritual.
He said
it's best to donate some merit
to the dead estate manager
to help him attain early liberation.
This way, I'll be free of the evil spirit,
and the Xie family
will also naturally be safe.
I
will give orders to prepare banknotes.
But the amount of money
isn't a small sum.
Three days.
Don't delay my ritual.
Certainly.
Alright.
By the way,
Old Madam Xie,
I have a cloak made of Yunshui satin
in Fourth Lady's hands.
I hope
she can also bring it along then.
What do you mean?
Nothing.
I just took a shine to Fourth Lady.
Three days later at noon,
Qingyuan will definitely
arrive on time.
Yan Rui has focused only
on our Xie family time and again.
But Hengtang is vast.
Since the wind is blowing,
the eaves bells of all families
should ring.
Celestial Master said
Danyue Pavilion
must be restored exactly as it was before.
It was really difficult for me.
I couldn't sleep for nights,
worrying about it.
But then I thought,
this concerns the family's reputation.
And Old Madam
[Danyue Pavilion]
gave me strict orders repeatedly.
So
I made up my mind.
Even if I had to risk my life,
I must get it done, right?
[Danyue Pavilion]
I've ordered someone to brew
the black tea you love
and keep it warm on the stove.
I wanted you to have a warm sip
as soon as you returned.
[Danyue Pavilion]
Look.
Look at this pitiful look.
If Baoxian weren't standing here,
I would really think
our Fourth Madam had returned.
Fourth Lady can certainly feel
the elders' care for her.
From the ornaments in this room,
it's evident that you and Second Madam
put a lot of effort.
It's my duty.
But the timber
looks like inferior fir wood
with a layer of paint on it.
Nonsense.
What inferior...
How could we
pass off inferior wood as quality one?
Although I don't know how favored
Fourth Madam was back then,
I heard that the items placed in this room
were all top-notch.
But right now, the items in this room
are nothing like them at all.
How?
Take a look.
Baoxian.
Fourth Lady.
Nanny.
Grandmother asked the second branch
to restore Danyue Pavilion.
I know
Second Madam is too busy usually.
She also has to manage the household.
These trivial matters
are all left for you to handle.
The accounts are complicated.
Baoxian just kindly wanted to remind you,
worrying you might be deceived by bad men.
Right.
Look.
Our Fourth Lady
is so reasonable.
Get better eyes and look carefully.
Look.
Over here.
And over here.
These are all top-quality
rosewood.
And the ornaments in the room
are top-notch items that can only be found
in the capital.
This grand Danyue Pavilion
now has the best furnishings
in our residence.
Don't be picky.
I like to be picky.
You damn servant.
Baoxian.
Look at her.
Nanny Na,
you'd better be careful.
I heard
that Grandmother hates people
who line their pockets the most.
If restoring Danyue Pavilion
causes a rift between you and others,
then my sin would be great.
You may not know this, Fourth Lady.
Our residence
has to both keep up appearances
and save money.
You know that Old Madam
never liked extravagance.
Yes.
You're right, Nanny.
No matter what,
thank you for your hard work.
It's my duty.
[Fuyu Fair]
Have a cup of tea.
You're indeed smart, Fourth Lady.
You and your mother
look so alike.
Looking at you,
I'm in a trance.
I heard that Lord Yan likes women
with slender hands.
You must take care of yours, Fourth Lady.
Get lost.
Are you waiting for dinner? Let's go.
My Lady, you're amazing.
[Danyue Pavilion]
Let's go.
This damn old woman.
She's always taking credit for herself.
She must have embezzled a lot of money.
Why hasn't this evil person
gotten her retribution yet?
Take it easy.
Real evil spirits
are all in people's hearts.
They can never be eliminated.
Little ones who rush to the front like her
will be dealt with sooner or later.
Now that you're confirmed as the mascot,
do you have any other plans, My Lady?
Where is Third Madam?
It's said that she had a relapse.
It's inconvenient for her to go out.
She's been hiding
in Hanxiang Parlor these days,
not daring to come out and see guests.
But the third branch is also pitiful,
suppressed everywhere.
Eldest Lady lives a life even worse than
that of a favored maid in the residence.
Can she hide herself from it?
[Danyue Pavilion]
It's not that easy.
By the way, what about the cloak?
Is it washed?
It's cleaned.
Shall we return it to Lord Yan's mansion?
It's not time yet.
You mean
we should wait?
But what are we waiting for?
Fourth Lady.
[Danyue Pavilion]
Old Madam wants to see you.
The wait is over.
Grandmother.
How is it?
Is the room comfortable?
Thank you for your concern, Grandmother.
Danyue Pavilion has been restored
by Second Madam and Nanny Rong very well.
That's good.
From now on,
this is your home.
Feel free to live here.
Everyone in the Xie family
will protect you.
Come here.
Sit next to me.
Yes.
I have
an important thing
for you to handle.
The day before yesterday,
I promised Lord Yan some banknotes.
Take that Yunshui satin cloak with you
and deliver them to him personally.
Grandmother, you must be joking.
In the outer courtyard,
aren't there servants to run errands?
No matter how many precious tribute teas
there are in the capital,
Lord Yan still
prefers Yunya tea.
It's refreshing.
Since you've joined the Xie family,
your life and fate
are tied to the Xie family.
I like your cleverness.
There are some things
that even if I didn't tell you,
you already knew.
Otherwise, that day,
on the boat,
you wouldn't have said those things to me.
Right?
I understood.
That's good.
How come it's you, Fourth Lady?
The Xie family is so inconsiderate.
They asked you to come alone?
Where is Lord Yan?
He's waiting for you in the courtyard.
Follow me please.
-Hurry up.
-Okay.
Hurry up.
His Lordship might have left
for some urgent matter.
Wait here please. I'll go find him.
How frivolous.
What are you looking at?
Are you that curious about me?
Why don't I
show you around?
Your Lordship.
I'm here to deliver banknotes
for my grandmother.
And that cloak.
I've had it cleaned.
I'm returning it to its owner.
Why do I remember
there is also Yunya?
Yunya is here.
Your Lordship.
The tea
needs to be stored carefully,
I've asked a servant to take it down.
But
do you really live in such a place?
Isn't this place good?
It has mountains, water, and wine,
as well as a beauties to admire.
Good.
Very good.
Then I hope you enjoy it.
I'll take my leave now.
I recently learned a new trick.
Since you're so knowledgeable,
why don't you take a look for me?
Turmeric water.
Plant ash.
This way,
one can conjure up a bloody
ghost-killing show.
Isn't it wonderful?
Your Lordship,
what are you talking about?
The Xie Residence is blessed
with great fortune.
How could those monsters and ghosts
possibly enter?
Right.
That's what I thought, too.
But what if the one that entered
is a cunning little fox?
You're so perceptive.
I made a fool of myself in front of you.
Fourth Lady, you always like to play
interesting tricks.
Starting fires with sugar balls.
Stabbing talismans with turmeric.
What about next time?
What will it be next time?
By the way,
Your Lordship,
these are perilla candies I made myself,
taught by my granny.
Please accept them.
Are they made from arsenic?
You must be joking.
How would I dare?
Why wouldn't you dare?
Poison, after all,
must be sugar-coated
to be appealing.
I added borneol and mint.
Interrogations are exhausting.
Keeping one in your mouth
will refresh yourself.
I have to go back to report.
I'll take my leave now.
[Virtue Blesses for Generations]
We must remember all of this.
When we grow up,
we must bring the truth to light
and bring the sinners to justice.
Every blood debt
has a name
[Spirit Tablet of the Late Ancestors
of the Xie Family]
and must be paid off.
My mom
was the best mom in the world.
I'll make those
who killed her
suffer dearly for this.
Mother.
[Virtue Blesses for Generations]
The Xie family already regards me
as their mascot.
I, as a chess piece,
have been swallowed by them.
[Spirit Tablet of the Late Ancestors
of the Xie Family]
Danyue Pavilion.
I've used their hands
to take it back for you.
[Spirit Tablet of the Late Ancestors
of the Xie Family]
This is just the beginning.
Rest assured.
Every single injustice,
I will clear them
one by one.
[A Legacy of Virtue for Eternity]
Since this show has begun,
I must make this good play go all the way
to its liveliest part
to be worth watching.